OK so first batch play with the site so
you will find this lucid flow chart link
from here OK so first cover the batch
create quiz side part.
So this batch create quiz I process
cheques whether the latest target on
batch run has been completed or not OK so
this will be happened in every regular
run.
First batch would be checked based upon
this,
our actual batch task flow would be
triggered.
OK,
here it will just check whether our
latest batch is completed or not.
OK,
now we latest target back my I mean like
by which columns it will say, yeah,
so it will let's go through it in the
core level.
So here I'll just give you high level
details.
So if the latest if John is completed,
the batch pre requisite task flow will
would be completed successfully.
And don't do batch task flow will be
triggered automatically for the regular
run and storm ranch OK for a regular run,
if the if the target zone batch and
status is not completed and notification
would be sent and the batch because the
task flow will fail and it must be
triggered manually after validation.
OK, OK.
And for restart rerun zone 1 rerun and
also for first time incremental also we
don't first time incremental one second.
So if the job fails in that case suppose
it is fixed.
OK, so manually we have to run,
miss prerequisite task we have to run or
the actual bad process we have to do.
It depends upon the IT depends upon the
situation.
Yeah, if they are like after validation,
if they are marking the status of the
latest batches completed,
then they they can trigger this batch
prerequisite task flow directly.
Otherwise if they are just trying to
ignore the failure but it will affect
again,
like if they want to ignore the failure
but just now and they want to start the
batch and they can directly trigger the
batch transfer.
It depends upon the situation.
But let gets the get this confirmation
from also this is what I'm saying OK,
OK for restart rerun zone 1 rerun
scenario and also for first time
incremental historical and catch up also
this is not required is what I'm thinking.
OK, let's let's ask this question.
OK.
For first time incremental history and as
you would be developing right have this
question.
So do we need to like trigger this batch
prerequisite task flow if we are loading
for historical catch up on first time
incremental load, OK.
But for restart rerun zone 1 rerun,
we don't directly target zone batch task
flow can can be triggered manually.
OK,
so in the lucid chart also I have just
given like this first June 2 table load
will be scheduled on stone branch as per
the scheduled time check for the June 2
late two months.
Is the scheduling app stone rich?
Yes, yes, it's the scheduling dot here.
It will check for the latest run.
If it is completed,
it will move on to the batch load.
If it is failed,
it will just send out a mail and manually,
manually we have to do this trigger
manually till the job completes
successfully.
OK,
and let's let's go to the IDM soup for
signed out.
OK,
we'll have ABC components under each and
every domain folder.
So if you see Dia common,
this will hold the common framework
related component.
Whenever we need those component,
those frameworks in any of our domain,
then we have to copy them to our specific
ABC folder and then we have to use.
OK, for now I'll just give you.
So in the Dai comment folder only ABC
components are there or other components
are also there even conflict driven
related pipelines that details are also
there so so ABC folders.
So entire ABC folder folder needs to be
copied in case of new domain correct?
This batch pay requisite should be copied
to the main folder because it's a task
for right?
So every batch will have their own own
batch prerequisite.
So this has to be copied based upon it
because that will take the values to
fetch the latest job using few parameters.
This has to be copied for each and every
batch.
OK, so in the start step what do we have?
So this previous website like this
particular task flow,
is it a like task flow under something or
it is the main task flow?
Main task flow let me show I can't run so
this has to be copied to main task flow.
Once we copy it here,
we'll just need to change the name
slightly based upon this.
So in the input fields we have to provide
the parameter file directory and
parameter filing.
OK there is only one mapping task here
which will check the latest latest latest
run details.
So it will it will need input parameters
like ABC, database name, schema name,
application layer name, domain name,
source name and target name.
OK so these are coming from the parameter
file correct?
So all these things first let me give you
a walk of the source code.
First here in this CTA we are trying to
get the batch ID and source batch ID OK.
So using source name, domain name,
application layer name,
target zone and EZ to philtre you asked
me right about this EZ to philtre.
We will be trying to get the batch ID and
source batch ID from batch metadata table
OK.
After that in this latest run we would be
using like we are trying to get the
status batch ID and batch run ID from
batch run stats table using the batch ID
that we got in the tab of city OK.
We're just doing an order by on this
descending OK.
Now it's Flash OK and we,
we are trying to just get the latest run
from the batch run stats using that.
We are just like we're we're just trying
to or like send out this batch ID,
application source batch,
the status and batch run ID.
OK,
We're trying to fix work on just a moment
from the batch, batch ID,
application source batch ID.
And then from this latest run,
we are getting the latest status and
batch run ID.
OK got it.
OK.
And then in the expression in the
expression flag we have a like we have a
parameter called script flag skip in our
param script flag.
This is used to skip if to skip the batch
run in case if my previous status is
failed.
So here I'm checking can you can you show
me the parameter file side by side for
this?
Here the parameter file is scattered
actually, but I'll show you that one.
So we would be using the same parameter
file whatever you're using for the batch
because whatever the input parameters
that are required for this transfer are
already pressing in the global part.
So target zone, source name, domain name,
target zone, application layer.
OK,
So what sense is you domain name at all
target to rule 2?
And what is the flag?
Some flag you were showing me that is
flag or something and we are just using
it for the code for that time.
You know parameter are getting from here
is it?
It's just a output parameter which would
be used in the latest steps of the task.
OK so here we are trying to set 1 value
to the skip flag.
So here is the expression if my status is
either started or failed then I'm marking
it as AY as it is N then you got this
right.
So in case if my latest batch run status
is straight in started or failed straight
then I should not do a second run for my
like next run for my target batch.
So that that is expression.
So started and failed means started and
failed means it will be low right?
Like it should be low in that case, right?
I mean the last run,
if the last run was failed,
the last it's automated failed.
Now it's automated regular run,
we don't have any manual intervention,
right?
So every time the system will check
whether my latest batch run of of my
current batch which I'm trying to load
now whether its latest run is completed
successfully or not.
If it is completed successfully,
then only we have to proceed with the
next run.
Otherwise we have to fix that issue first.
Otherwise for like for some like in order
to have like add this next run,
they have to decide and manipulate the
entry in such a way so that next run
would be you would be triggered.
So whatever what what I can think of is
in case it might status is started in in
my previous one,
but it is not handled by anyone.
It is as it is then a notification would
be sent out stating that this patched 1
is not started because of this reason,
because the previous one is already
started.
They will they will validate and then
they have to find a solution whether they
have like based upon the scenario again.
So,
so if they just want the bypass that if
they want to bypass that run they can
directly upgrade the status to complete
and trigger this batch pre requested task
flow.
Otherwise if they want to skip this and
do a restart,
they can directly run the batch task flow.
This action should be done by the team
whoever this notification is sent.
But this skip plan means like what is the
like ultimate goal of this this skip like,
like skip like, like will it?
If it is, why what happens?
And if it is no N, what happens?
Yeah, yeah.
So if my status is either started or
failed, it will be why else it would be N?
OK,
we'll we'll see how it is used in the
task flow.
OK.
This,
we are setting this value to A and and
our parameter skip flag.
And we are also setting value for batch
ID and batch generating.
OK.
And then ID and ID whatever we are
getting OK,
then moving on to this back to here,
whatever the other transformations are
there are just have like added for
standard purpose of Iscs as we need a
targeted philtre,
it will just block it is false.
It won't make any interest.
We just added these two to to as per the
ISS standard to have a target in the
mapping.
OK, OK,
going to this task loop 1 if here we are
using that skip, skip flag value.
If it is why when?
When it would be?
Why?
It would be Why when my batch status is
either started or failed.
If my latest batch status is started or
failed then it will send a notification.
It will send a notification like this
prerequisite failed like that.
It will this.
This is the subject like this is the body
of the mail.
The latest batch run is has not been
completed successfully.
Please check the batch status and rerun
the task flow once the batch is completed
successfully.
We have to rerun the task flow only when
the previous batch is completed
successfully.
OK, if it is completed,
if the status is not failed or not
started then it would be completed.
Then In that case it will just go to and
and this task flow run would be complete
it successfully then our batch task flow
actual batch task flow would be triggered
that this would be happen in the stone
branch field.
But whenever my latest batch run is not
completed successfully then it will fail
this task flow and it will send out a
notification.
So in that case my batch run won't start
it.
So that could that should be handled
manually.
OK.
But it is like this is confusing for me
because of the like, you know,
parameter names.
It means generally if it is why it means
like this,
this process needs to be skipped like in
general, logically.
So I,
I that's why I ask like what it means.
What is the intention behind having the
risk?
We are skipping the batch run.
We are skipping the batch run, right.
So in that way I just calculate OK, next,
next, coming to the batch preload.
So I'll show you batch task for as well.
And I'm showing you the batch task loafer
account.
So this is how the batch task will look
like first.
So in the previous one,
did we need to provide any table name or
anything?
No, right.
No.
We just need to provide the parameter
file.
That's it.
Parameter file also.
We just need to have those four,
four or five parameters we are having to
get the batch ID, right?
That's it.
So under here also under 1 batch,
there could be multiple tables or jobs,
right?
Yeah,
1 batch will have multiple table loads
which are called jobs.
Yes, OK.
So actually we'll have in a in in
parameter in input field,
we have parameter file directory,
parameter file name,
audit user ID and batch task flow name.
So these four are the input parameters.
We have to provide the hardware and
values for parameter file name and
parameter file directory.
From here these values are usually
passing to the job level task force all
these OK,
so then we'll have batch preload.
I'm just giving you high level.
If this is if this task gets failed
because of any execution error,
a notification would be sent out and this
task flow would be failed.
OK and once if this is completed
successfully then our actual batch task
flow would sorry job level task flow
would be triggered and all the job task
flows would be arranged in the runtime as
per the run order.
So.
But for here we have just taken 1 task
flow because batch 1 can be assignment
this one error count OK here we have
temporary variables.
Also we have temporary variables like
error count and temporary batch status.
The initial value which is provided for
this is error count and batch status is
null.
We don't have any batch status.
So if this is if any batch task any job
level task for gets paid error count
value would be incremented.
Initially it is 0 right?
If any job level task flow gets
incremented,
it is it gets incremented OK based upon
this error count if it is greater than 0.
If it is equal to 0 that means if no job
task flow gets failed then then only its
value would be 0.
In that case,
temporary batch status would be assigned
with C Otherwise it would be assigned
with if OK based upon this temporary
batch status.
Our actual batch status in the batch
transcripts would be updated here.
OK, OK.
And then if if this component gets failed
because of any some execution issue,
a notification would be sent out and the
staff flow gets failed.
But these are just error handle at the
task flow level set.
It's not like related to ABC.
So this batch task flow after this batch
post load based upon the batch temp,
batch status C or F based upon that a
notification would be sent.
If it is C,
this notification would be sent and the
task flow would be executed successfully.
If it is FF failure,
notification would be sent out and this
task flow gets failed.
I'm just giving you high level status.
Now go to let's let's have a walk through
of the batch failure.
So for batch preload,
these are the input parameters that is
required parameter file name,
parameter file sorry,
directory file name and ABC database name,
ABC schema name, application layer name,
audit user ID, domain name,
source name and target whatever the
values that for which initial values not
provided, right.
So those will be directly fetched from
the static parameter file.
OK, let's move on to this logic.
OK,
here I want to explain you in the LLD
first.
OK batch preload process.
The batch preload process will create a
single record in the batch translation
table at the start of the batch execution.
This process will perform the following
steps in sequence.
It will using the input parameters like
application layer name, force name,
domain name and target zone.
The system will vary for the batch
metadata to retrieve the active batch ID
where is active flag equal to Y.
It will try to get the active batch ID
based upon the retrieved batch ID.
The system will identify the latest batch
run from batch status OK.
It will just get the latest batch one
second first batch metadata it is getting
the batch ID and all.
Then after that based on the retrieved
batch ID, there is only test, right?
There will be single batch ID only for
that combination.
Yeah, there will be only single batch ID.
There should be only single batch ID from
the batch batch matrix with these details.
So after that like these two are the
common steps for what we got it got it.
So it is basically using the input
parameters.
It's time to get the latest batch run ID
along with the batch ID.
Yeah,
it will get the latest batch run details.
OK,
we will discuss how the details would be
used for populating values into this
table for historical load.
These are the execution types.
Historical load, catch, upload,
first time, incremental, regular run,
restart, rerun, zone 1, rerun.
These are the execution types.
Let's discuss 1 by 1.
So first historical historical load.
But one question historical load like you
said it is it is not implemented, right.
It is not implemented, yes,
you would be taking care like I'm just
giving you the points what which needs to
be covered as part of bash so that it
would be easier to compare and develop
the.
So I'll be needing what is currently and
then what needs to be done both.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
So historical load.
How they are planning to have the
historical load is if a batch needs to be
processed for historical data from
Teradata to Snowflake Zone 2 via zone one,
this will also be done via zone 1 only.
But in the historical data,
data would be will be taken from Teradata
directly.
In the current state Teradata is the
target database.
In future state historical load Teradata
is the source database.
You got the difference right.
So the process will read that run as
historical load.
For historical load a new record will be
created manually in batch run stats.
So I record.
So batch entry would be one second this
Arora table.
So I haven't worked on this.
So what is that Arora table?
All the ABC tables are in this Arora or
something, right?
So is it negative Mark, is it?
Yeah, yeah, all the ABC tables in Arora.
We have few ABC temp tables in Snowflake.
I'll tell you the details of those temp
tables later whenever the component
discussion comes, but for now,
I'll show you the batch metadata.
OK, let's, let's have this.
OK, let's.
And this Arora table, like, is it like,
is it completely different from data?
Data and software Arora is different.
Arora.
Arora post Arora is relative.
Arora is just a post sequel database of
AWS service AWS.
Arora is a service database of AWS.
So it is currently having post pre sequel.
It is a sequel type post pre sequel.
OK, so batch metadata looks like this.
So then why it is like this?
ABC tables are in here and the source
table in somewhere and then the target
table is somewhere like like can really
ABC tables remains in the same database
where the target is right?
OK this is because of June 1 as we are
asked to leverage the same ABC tables
which are used by June 1.
So we are also using the same ABC tables
which were in Aurora.
There ABC code mostly lies in land,
glue whatever like services related to
AWS.
So arrow is also service of AWS right?
So they are using the same database there.
Also.
The purpose of June 1 is to bring the
data from source to S3.
They they will just drop the files in S3
from S3.
We'll have Snowflake managed iceberg
tables in Snowflake which will directly
pointing to the S3 files there.
OK.
Can you come again this one?
This is related to zone one.
I'm just giving you the information
whatever I know.
So zone one will bring data from direct
source system to S3 S 3 is again AWA
service.
I just wanted to know the zone 1 is more
around AWA services.
So that is the reason why they have ABC
tables also in Arora service which is
better to AWS.
And we are asked to leverage the same ABC
tables even for John 2.
We're using it even though if even though
our target table database is not like
we're leveraging as per the require like
ask we are using these tables.
Hope you got the answer.
Yeah.
So how the full video working is working
here, We'll,
we'll discuss this whenever this job load
comes.
That is the reason why we are having the
timetables.
We have timetables in Snowflake, OK,
in order to enable full PDO,
have the full pushdown optimization in
our load,
we are having timetables in Snowflake.
That is, that isn't OK.
And I'm just showing you the job metadata
entry, which is made for CCO account, OK?
So batch name, batch description,
active flag, CCO dot data Roman,
all these things, OK, And batch run stats,
right?
You asked me about batch run stats.
Let me show you.
Oh OK so in case of first time
incremental or any first time incremental
history load catch up load an entry would
be manually made here.
So while making the manual entry what are
the feeds to be populated?
Those details I have provided here in
batch run manual.
Manual entry needs to be provided.
Isn't it automatic?
It is automated for regular and restart
run.
But for educate scenarios like historical
load which is one time catch upload which
is one time first time incremental,
it is one time and rerun of June 2 or
June 1 which is very occasional.
Whenever like this the situation comes,
they have to do this right?
So it means none of zone 1 and zone 2.
What does that mean?
Don't do rerun?
It's it's just like scenarios whenever
any code logics change or whenever they
want to reload the data for specific data.
Wait no no, it depends.
Depends on the requirement.
Whenever they want to do a rerun,
basically rerun mean rerunning was
deletion of the old data and they want to
have the new data for the time period.
They have to mention the like they have
to provide the time period also whenever
they are doing their rerun.
And zone 1 rerun is whenever any rerun
happened in the zone 1 table then we have
to reprocess that data right in our table.
So that is where this Zone 1 rerun comes,
OK, that is more related to functional,
not related to ABC actually,
but we are we have to handle that
scenario also.
Now how we are handling that scenario as
part of ABC, I'll, I'll tell you.
OK.
So first coming to the historical load,
if a batch needs to be processed OK for a
historical load,
a manual entry should be made into the
batch run stats table.
Whenever we are making the entry into the
batch run stats table,
a new execution run ID will be asset any
entry which is made into the batch run
stats right?
And you batch run ID would be assigned
that means for sure because that's a
primary.
So I'm not giving that detail here.
And new execution run ID would be
assigned,
rerun indicator would be H status would
be started sourcing start time would be
1919 hundred 0101 sourcing end time would
be maximum of GRS defined timestamp
across all tables for a given batch.
So GRS timestamp column is present in all
the target table OK in all the if you are
a refined time stamp that is next OK you
have something hello OK JRS refined time
stamp is the column in all the target
tables of zone one.
It would be there for all the tables.
So we have to like get get the maximum
JRS time stamp across all tables for a
given batch.
So like this is the this is how the our
sourcing end time should be populated
while we are making a manual entry.
OK,
so in the batch related details or anyone
anywhere it is not there this year is
define time stamp.
No, it is not there.
You can check which file once on this
column.
So it is kind of a real.
So if if they are planning to do this
historical load from 1st 19119 hundred to
first or December 31st of 2026 till this
time they want to do historical load like
they want to get the data from you know
from Teradata to Snowflake.
So then they will they are trying to load
till December 31st.
So they will check whether what is the
maximum GRS refined time stamp that we
have on that particular day.
They will check and they will assign that
value to it.
So for development and testing purpose
you might take any value I guess.
But during the actual historical load,
it's their responsibility to get the
maximum GRS refund different times of
value from all the tables.
And that's the only one.
Yeah.
OK.
So they'll be providing it to us for this
entry right in that tier usually.
Yeah,
it depends like in real time scenario
they have to take.
But for testing purpose,
you can check which one.
I think you can take any random value
because what I'm thinking maybe today's
date you can take it for just for testing
you can take is what I'm thinking.
OK in real time during the production,
they have to go configure like maybe like
if they're asked, they will.
This is the process.
This is the value that needs to be
populated into sourcing area OK which is
maximum refined time stamp across all
tables that are coming under a specific
match specific match.
During historical load processing.
Batch prerequisites will not be evaluated.
Since the records are created manually,
Batch preload will not perform any
additional changes and execution will
begin and stop.
It will not be evaluated.
Batch preview site will not be validated.
Means like it's not it's not a regular
run.
So this would be for the first time.
What is the point of we have to directly
trigger the batch flow?
Yes, yeah.
And also as the batch pre batch in like
we have made an entry into the batch run
stretch table manually.
We don't need to do anything as part of
batch batch preload like we do.
We should not make any entry,
we should not make any change to the
entry which is already made manually.
That's what this sentence means.
OK,
so we and is that logic there or is
implemented?
It has to be, it has to be there.
It has to be there.
It's not implemented, right, RIA,
it's not.
So just let me know like I like,
I guess like nothing,
none of this is implemented,
but still just let me know.
So in case anything among these points
are already implemented,
that's not implemented.
History catch up first time incremental
whatever related to this has not been
implemented at any step of the at any
stage of the ABCD.
OK,
this has to be implemented and ABC
runtime tables required for historical
loader pass transfer, job run set,
job error, stress job rule, execution log,
job rule,
error detail and balance reconstruction.
Because why I have provided all these
details, right?
This is LLD like whoever looking at this
for the first time should have all the
details like if anyone,
if anyone is having any question if they
are looking into this,
they have to understand, right?
That is the reason why I'll try to keep
every point possible like every possible
point here.
If we see runtime tables required for
yeah, yeah,
not choosing ETL data ingestion source
window here,
they are not using ETL data ingestion
source window OK.
The historical load would be executed
based on one time range provided in the.
So there is no need for the table ETL
data ingestion source window.
The main significance of this ETL data
ingestion source window table is to
provide the sourcing window for the
incremental load, right?
But in the historical load,
we are not using it.
We are using the dates provided in the
patch and stats directly for for
historical load.
OK, OK.
And the the data which is like takes from
the source,
it is always stored in the batch run
status table as the source sourcing start
time and in time right here that is the
window like sorry,
what come again this sourcing start time
and sourcing in time that is the like
window by using which the source table is
like data is safe and in general OK and
in normal load, sorry, go ahead.
And in normal load, so regular load.
So are these two fields loaded by using
values from some those EPL data ingestion
or something correct?
OK so here this is what I'm thinking.
If my execution type is historical or my
batch latest batch to even indicator
research,
then in that case let's have two
parameters, yeah,
sourcing stratum and sourcing end time.
So whatever the latest sourcing stratum
and sourcing end time we have in the best,
otherwise let's discuss it at the last
whatever that logic needs to be
implemented as part of.
Yeah,
I think that will be better if we talk it
last.
We you can give suggestion now like,
but finally we'll need to either way have
a like discussion about that one,
what is needed and all.
Yeah, OK.
So then critical check there only here
what are the cheques that are performing
is null check should be performed on key
columns for the load happened between
zone one source to zone route.
As historical load is also happening via
zone one,
we have to do a historic critical check.
So just like normal regular route how we
are doing null cheques for key column,
we have to do the same for this and
source and target count validation
between source and source and target
should happen.
This will be taken care by job and stress
table that so one question before at this
point.
So this critical check thing.
So generally in all the target table we
like how how the primary key is our key
column is like is is it one particular
column or there could be like multiple
records for one.
It will be provided by data modelling
team.
And these are all like which type of
tables is it?
Like is it type 1, type 2 or what type 2?
It depends on the functionality of the of
the asset.
But in producer and CCO all tables are
SCD type 2 and fewer static tables.
I think 3 tables are static tables.
I don't know how they are handling that
static table.
I don't know whether they're using ABC or
not.
Also I don't directly using some migrate
or something.
I don't know about those details.
But as of now in the build,
whatever happening in the IDMC,
they're using SAT type 2 table.
As of now being in the future state,
we might come across different flow types
OK and balance sheet cancellation.
Also if there are any amount columns,
then we have to perform the balance
reconciliation also for the data load
happening between the zone and source and
zone to source OK,
zone to target OK and then coming to the
catch up load, catch up load,
if our data needs to be processed for the
for the data to load from Teradata to
Snowflake zone one second this source and
target count validation between zone one
source and zone 2 target.
So is it done in the regular load as well?
Yeah,
it it will be done in the job run stats,
right in the job run stats post load.
Oh, OK, OK.
Normal source and target count validation
it is yeah.
Normal thing Zone 1 and zone 2 it is
mentioned.
That's very good conversation.
Yeah,
it's just normal thing only because my
siti mentioned this point in her notes in
in the design steps.
So I thought it would be better to have
this.
But one question right.
Account validation is between like in the
job it and down status it is between zone
1 target and zone 2 target, right?
Because zone 1 target is our source,
correct, correct.
So like if this one, this statement,
is it correct?
Like zone one source and zone 2 target
correct?
How many?
OK.
Yeah.
So we are having this ABC framework for
the historical load happening from
Teradata to Zone 2 table, OK.
This is business requirement.
How we are doing this?
We are doing the Teradata to zone one
load using some demigrator framework that
is different, OK.
Our purpose is to load from zone 1 to
zone 2.
OK,
So our ABC framework should should idea
here for this requirement.
Zone 1-2, Zone 2, that's it.
So zone 1 would be always our source.
Zone 2 is our target for historical as of
now.
OK, one second.
OK, OK.
I bought you what you are trying to say.
But this particular like statement is
like it is.
It is like indicating like zone 1 like
source code zone 1 because basically data
data.
It seems like that that means we can keep
like this zone 1 which is source.
It's better, yeah,
because it was implying like zone one
source,
like source for zone 1 and then target
for zone 2.
Yeah, Oh my God.
I'm just for it.
This preload cash preload is also taking
very much of OK, then catch upload.
OK, you,
you were there then if you were there
like then it would have like it would not
take that much time.
But if if kind of I have to take that I'm
taking from you.
And the one kind of thing that yeah.
But what I want to like inform leads is
about this time that it is taking for
reverse Kitty and Kitty it is taking more
than two hours.
Yeah.
That that you need to infer especially
you need to inform because you were
working on some other important steps as
well, right?
Yeah, yeah, I'll inform them.
I'll inform them.
Yeah.
Like let's have this discussion.
That's why I'm first if a batch needs to
be processed for that.
So actually if they are trying to load
from they're trying to get all the data
from Teradata to Snowflake,
then December 31st Aishwarya,
like is it possible for the historical
load to add that statement that you said,
right?
That the like total name is data data to
Snowflake.
This historical load,
but from a data data to like zone 1 is
basically loading by using the migrator
tool and which part the ABC will cover.
If you can add that as well,
that will be helpful.
Zone 2 is responsible,
but the load happening up from zone 1 to
zone 1.
And also about the D migrator tool also
you can mention that that's OK.
Like we don't need that.
I don't know whether the framework is
exactly just D migrator rod.
This is document right?
So I just don't want to have it.
But we can check with FAM and we can add
OK zone is responsible zone to ABC.
Let me ABC is responsible for the load
happening from zone 1 to zone 2.
OK, So catch up load is nothing,
but it is also,
it is also load related to the data load
from Teradata to Snowflake only.
But here I'll give you a difference
between this to historical and catch up.
So we're running till December 31st,
right?
There would be huge volume of data which
cannot be loaded into our Snowflake
tables in a day, in a day or two, right.
So it might take another 10 days or 20
days.
We we are not sure depending upon the
volume of the data,
it will take time to load data from
direct data to Snowflake.
The initial historical what I'm talking
about.
So whatever the so I'm on the December
31st I triggered the historical load.
Now I am on John 10.
So my historical load has completed
whatever the data that is not loaded is
from John first to John 10 right?
I will be loading this data using a run
called catch it load.
OK,
this would be happened because it's just
10 days of data which which can be done
within one hour 2.
So from the next day onwards first time
incremental would be started.
But for the first time incremental in
order to have that data like in order to
avoid any data loss,
we are taking the sourcing start time
from Jan 7th.
Even though the catch upload is happened
till Jan 10th.
We would be taking sourcing starting from
the for the this the first time
incremental is from Jan 7th or 8th.
Because if anyway if the records are
already present in the target,
they would be marked data unchanged.
But we just to ensure that there is no
data loss,
we are using this technique for first
time incremental.
OK, so just one second.
Can you come again with the just just the
timeline Like I got the concept just the
timeline.
Just give me example how like what will
be my date of historical load?
What will be the my time frame for the
catch up load?
What will be for the incremental load?
I'll give you a date from 1900 to
December 31st 2026.
I'm loading historical data.
OK, I triggered my historical task flow.
So the load completed on Jan 10th.
So on John 10th I will be loading data
from December 31st whatever sourcing
January 10th data loaded till January
10th historical data loaded.
It took it took ten days to load data.
This is an assumption.
It took data it took to load data from
Teradata to Snowflake.
OK.
On John 10th,
whatever the sourcing end time,
which I use it for historical load,
that would be my sourcing end time in my
cache upload and sourcing.
Sourcing end time would be my current
time stamp value.
OK,
this event catch up entry that needs to
be populated into the batch run stretch
is also a manual entry.
OK,
I'm just giving you the dates here on
John 10th from from January 1st to
January 10th,
I'll be loading data from Teradata to
Snowflake as part of catcher execution
after that OK After that,
for the first time incremented,
I'll be loading from January 7th to
current time one second profiles
historical 1900 to 31st January.
OK.
Oh, 31st December, 31st December, sorry.
Yeah, December.
Yeah.
Then the sourcing start date,
start date for catch that will be,
it would be something around like
December 31st at 12:00 AM or 1:00 AM,
whatever, whatever,
whenever they triggered,
whatever the time that they want to keep,
they keep OK.
And for catch upload my sourcing end time
start time would be my previous sourcing
end time.
Whatever the sourcing end time that is
there for historical load that would be
my sourcing start time for catch upload.
And what will be the insight end time?
End time would be depends upon the
requirement only.
But as as per my assumption historical
load took 10 days right on January 10th,
I want to do a catch upload.
So then I would be taking January 10th
current time stamp as my end time for
catch upload.
Like all these decisions might differ at
the production environment,
but this is the basic assumption that we
are having for this design.
OK.
And for first time incremental I would be
loading from three days prior to the
sourcing end time of the catch up load.
So we would be doing three days prior.
So that means first time incremental load
would happen from January 7th to current
time stamp.
So whatever the date is,
it will be like it needs to be 3 day
prior to the catch up load, catch up load.
So that that includes the time stamp like
if it is like today,
if it is supposed the sourcing and time
for catch up load was 7:00 PM seventh of
18th of January, 7:00 PM,
then the incremental load should be 7th
of January, 7:00 PM only, right?
Or it needs to be from 12:00 AM?
Yeah, it depends.
Seven 7th of January they can take any
anytime because they can even take 2:12
AM.
So if they are doing historical load
every day at 1:00 AM,
it's also my assumption.
So they can take July, sorry,
January 7th 1:00 AM to January 11th 1:00
AM.
So this is my first time incremental load.
So if they are planning to do the
incremental load from the next from the
very next day of this catch up load, OK,
this historical load, catch up load,
incremental load,
all these are handling using manual
entries, right?
These date might be different,
but this is the basic assumption behind
the that's OK.
OK,
and how should be the surfing in time for
an incremental first time?
It can be current time stamp Anyway that
is also handled using manual entry so
they can keep anytime.
But what I'm thinking is because from if
they are decided,
if they decided to have the batch run
regular batch run daily at 1:00 AM,
then they would prefer to have the batch
end time at at 1:00 AM even though
they're triggering at 2:00 AM or 3:00 AM
or even in the 9:00 AM any time they
might be taking it.
It depends.
OK, you're getting right.
These would be yeah, added manually.
So we don't need to worry much.
But from from the Jan 12th onwards our
ABC framework should handle that our
stone branch based upon the scheduling it
will be automate.
But this all also needs to be these three
cases is needs to be implemented in ABC
like man entry will be manual but the job
load and everything will be done, yes.
So for historical and catch,
we like the sourcing stratum and end time
should be populated from batched and
stats, right?
So far that we have to have in our
parameters in order to pass to the job
load.
In case of first time incremental,
we just don't need to do anything,
but we just need to pass some batch ID,
batch and ID execution and ID to the next
steps.
That's it.
Usually for any type of the load,
for any type of execution,
we would be passing batch ID,
batch run ID, execution, run ID,
all those batch and then 4th batch
execution and a few details we would be
passing from job run stats.
OK, sorry, batch run stats preload.
OK, so you'll get it.
Like where to make the change even even I
would be there, right?
Uh huh.
OK, OK, let's let's again go back here.
Then during catch upload processing,
I think catch upload the answer.
So catch upload,
I'm just giving here the definition about
it.
So for a catch upload,
a new record will be created manually in
batch run stats and new execution run ID
will be assigned.
Read and indicator would be seen.
Status would be started sourcing,
start time sourcing and time sourcing.
Start time would be sourcing end time of
prior prior successfully completed batch
which would be my historical.
That's wrong.
In the bracket you add historical it
would be historical only anyways.
But yeah I'm giving it sourcing.
End time will be populated as Max of GRS
refined time stamp like this.
So they are not giving the exact this has
to be taken like current time stamp would
be taken.
They are taking maximum GRS refined time
stamp.
OK,
so that will they will be only providing
or we have to check it out that you have
to check with spam.
Yeah,
most probably whoever in the production
support, I think they think if they are,
if we have to trigger the run,
then we have to take care of all these
things.
No, Bing MC is fine,
but I'm I'm talking about this GRS
timestamp.
Yeah, yeah, we can check this file this,
but make a note of it like whatever the
questions you have now which we which
which we get to get the answers from
Swami because just jot all of them and
send send those questions in that mail to
spam.
OK.
And during catch upload processing,
batch prerequisites will not be evaluated
since the records are manually created
into the job batch inserts.
No additional changes would be done to
this in batch preload.
OK execution will be begin at job preload.
This is the same thing every CE runtime
tables are use space the same.
We are not using this ETL data edition 01
second since just a moment.
Since the records are created manually,
batch preload will not perform any
additional changes and execution will
begin at job reload.
Additional changes made like what you
were implying,
like it is already insert is already made
that's why it shouldn't insert any entry.
So it should insert 0 in records in that
case.
Yeah, that's it.
OK, OK, these are the same, I got it.
But you can provide like one line of
statement around that OK here,
which will not perform any additional
changes for the and true additional
changes additional yeah,
additional entries.
I think it will be it's OK.
Like even for the entry also we should
not make any change, right?
And we won't be performing as the end it
it implies spray, OK?
We're we are making that entry manually
for this purpose only, right?
We should not, Yeah,
but but in the normal regular one,
this job preload will be making a entry,
right?
Correct.
And in case the previous batch was failed,
in that case what will it do that will be
taken care of by P drop the request batch
or something process, right?
So each time this batch batch preload
will each time will make a new NC only.
There is no case of like loading 0
records otherwise, right?
OK, yeah, it won't, It won't.
Like we are handling the scenario using
manual entry.
So in that Case No wonder it would be
created as part of.
That's what it is taking.
It is saying then batch will not will not
perform this.
This statement is not correct.
I'll just copy the statement from the
notes.
Let let it be like once you develop it
right,
whatever you feel that would be suited,
we can add that area funnel.
Let it be OK.
We,
we can update this as per our design
later, like as per our implementation, OK,
Otherwise you can suggest me,
I'll just update it.
So many additional changes instead of
additional changes or or you can add one
line that or or it will not make a new
entry or something.
Because this this a little bit vague my I
don't know, like the notes,
maybe some kind of functional or
something.
But this is the low level design, right?
So at least one line should be there that
it will not make any new entry as it is
already existing, right.
So you can add it and highlight it.
Like if you want,
I can check and rewrite the philtre and
properly you can highlight this,
but I will just take it.
Yeah, it's OK.
Do you want me to help any any one of
them just highlight.
I will take one of them.
So ABC runtime we're not using ETL data
integration source window because we are
using the sourcing start and sourcing
from the bastion stretch directly.
So we are not using it and then critical
X needs to be performed for that.
One question here,
this data integration I know you will
cover it later but like when it is
triggered like is it automated?
Like when is the time this particular
data integration is triggered flow?
It will be in the job task two.
It will be in the job preload.
It would be after job run stats preload
after making the entry into the job run
stats preload this week.
So I don't know how to skip this.
We have to figure out OK and from that
like this data integration table again my
batch reload source,
sourcing start time and time is updated.
Sourcing start time,
sourcing end time columns are present in
ETL attention sourcing window.
Batch translation is also having sourcing
start time and sourcing window.
We are using the sourcing start time,
sourcing end time of batch translation
for historical and ink catch up.
Whereas sources start time and sourcing
end time in the ETL data injection is
used for the rest of the execution rights.
OK.
But for the regular case,
in that case how this sourcing in time
and start time is populated?
Is it not populated for the regular load?
For regular load also it is populated.
OK in ******* structure you are talking
it may be populated but the values won't
be used.
Nedika asked her to populate populated
from the like so for that population.
So will it be like, yeah, well,
suppose in the preload this entry is made
in the batch down status.
OK, in the.
I got your question yeah, I,
I'll show you in the code like what is
the value that needs to be populated for
sourcing startum and.
And yeah.
And when it is populated, yeah, I, I,
I'll tell you.
OK, let's OK,
if you're good on this like same critical
cheques, count validation,
balance reconstruction,
whatever we are doing for historical load,
we would be doing the same here.
OK,
Then moving on to the first time
incremental load,
first time incremental load either
initial incremental run after the
historical and catch up load is completed.
OK, this,
this will also be from zone 1 to zone 2,
but zone 1 is taking data from direct
source system this time, OK,
for incremental load,
a new entry would be created in batch and
stretch.
A new execution run ID would be assigned,
rerun indicator would be I status would
be started and sourcing start time would
be overall start time from the last three
days of catching.
This is what I mentioned to you.
And sourcing end time would be my zone 1
batch end time.
OK, zone 1 batch end time.
So whatever the source source batch,
let me check source in bracket LGB zone,
highlight this particular line in yellow,
OK this particular line.
And during the incremental load crossing
during the first time incremental.
Using the faster incremental load costing,
batch predict site will not be evaluated.
Since the records are created manually,
Batch preload will not perform any
additional changes and execution will
start at job preload.
No new entry would be made into job run
stats OK and ABC runtime tables.
We will use all the ABC runtime tables OK
ATL DATA INJECTION in the table ATL DATA
INJECTION source window,
but the source indecent source window
will not be used.
Sorry EPL data injection source window
will not be used right for this data set
we for this load type.
For this execution type first time
incremental we would be using detailed
data ignition source window only.
Here we like Spyam has given the details
like sourcing start time should be
populated from the sourcing start time of
batch run stats.
What we are doing a manual entry right
into batch, into the batch acceptable.
So whatever the sourcing end time that we
have provided during that manual entry
that needs to be populated to this,
so to this ETL data injection source
window.
This value should be consistent across
all tables for the batch OK and stored in
UTC.
It should be in UTC whatever the sourcing
stratum while we are making entry, right?
Follow the new or regular new scenes,
new or regular scenario.
OK.
And this EPL data ingression source
window like this,
this table will be loaded automatically
right from the from where drop below.
Yeah,
it it would be loaded automatically for
regular run.
But for first time incremental we have to
add these logics.
If my execution type is first time
incremental,
then we have to update the code in the
ATL data initial.
Yeah, OK.
Basically we need to this logic which you
are saying we need to apply in in the
code.
Yeah, it has to apply, yes.
So and then critical cheques,
source cheques, balance cheques,
it's it is just same.
And in in our param exhibition type would
be zone 2 first time incremental.
This would be the execution type like
this has to be the format and then new or
regular batch execution when is the
latest just so just let me be clear.
So for historical 1.
So my batch force and in time will be
populated from the batch run status table.
Then from first time incremental load it
will be populated from the batch like it
will be populated from the data
integration table.
But the data integration tables start
time and end time will be populated from
the batch run status thing which was
manually entered.
No,
only start time would be would be
populated from the from there end time.
It end time would be populated from
source job end time.
So this is different just sourcing start
time would be populated from the batch
and stats.
OK, sourcing end time, we will take it.
We'll like we'll we will like we will get
we will discuss about this in that
component.
Yeah, OK, bad.
So don't think but in time is populated
from posting in time will be done work
through.
And what about the catch up law from
where it is?
It will be which in which step both
history and catch up,
then coming to new and regular.
From here onwards the code is already
implemented.
If the latest June 2 batch is completed,
the process will insert a new record with
status started sourcing start time.
Sourcing start time would be previous
June 2 batch sourcing end time like just
previous batch run.
Sourcing end time would be it's a
sourcing start time.
Sourcing end time would be latest June 1
batch end time with status completed or
partial OK and execution run ID but it
will be new.
Execution and audit columns would be
operated and batch and flag would be N
This is for regular scenario and
execution type would be new OK and then
restart execution.
If the latest zone 2 batch run is failed
or started and rerun indicator equal to
north then the process will treat will
treat the run as a restart.
If my previous status is failed or
started and rerun indicator equal to
north then the process will treat the run
as restart.
For restart a new batch run stats record
would be inserted with same execution run
ID, source,
starting and sourcing item as well as the
latest zone 2 batch run status is filled
or started and redone indicator is in the
process field status run as a restart OK
and and.
And that means like the prerequisite
batch will be triggered or no?
No, if the return indicator is in no.
I told you right here for restart OK,
for restart rerun zone 1 rerun directly
the target zone batch task for must be
triggered manually.
No prerequisite.
Yeah, there is a no.
OK, are you good?
Can I continue this 1?
This we done indicator like was it
mentioned the values like Y&N?
What is the like meaning of this values
for Y&N?
Is it mentioned anywhere?
Sorry this we done indicator.
What happens if it is Y?
What happens if it is N?
Is it mentioned anywhere?
Yeah, it is mentioned.
For now,
just use this like if my status is
started or failed and I don't need to go
trip one to north,
then this run would be considered as tray
star.
I'll tell you about why in the below
below.
It's OK.
And I've also mentioned read an indicator
for these Also read an indicator C then
try read an indicator here.
Read an indicator would be N while making
the entry.
If my previous T run indicator is equal
to N then it will start.
Assume that run as a restart.
For a restart and you batch run it would
be inserted with the same insufficient
run ID sourcing start time,
sourcing entom as per the previous prior
run.
Whatever the prior run is having values
for these three fields right,
the same values would be populated for
the new entry OK.
If the previous record for the same
execution done ID is in status status,
the record will be updated to fail before
inserting the new record.
So if the previous status is started,
then it will update the status to fail
and also it will make a new entry with
status status OK.
Data processing will resume from the
point of failure.
Jobs already completed successfully will
not be reprocessed OK Job's already
completed if the if the.
If the file job has already loaded data
into the target table,
cleanup will be performed prior to
restart.
OK prior to restart in the sense prior to
the restart job role.
So it would be automated OK and batch run
flag would be end for this entry.
Whatever we are making batch run flag
would be END only in the scenario
execution type would be restart.
Batch tree requisite will not be
evaluated during restart processing.
OK restart the handling rules.
If the latest batch run is failed,
insert a new record with the same like.
The system will insert a new record with
same run ID as per the latest batch run.
If the batch run status is failed,
update the execution.
The process let me write the process
updates the existing record status to
fail 1st and then it inserts a new record
with the same execution.
So I'm just giving you high level
information here.
Good.
I'll be good.
Yeah, restart and rerun.
What is the difference between Yeah,
let me let me complete rerun also.
Then we'll discuss the like.
If you if you still have confusion,
we can discuss read and execution if a
batch must be reprocessed for any bag
dated date range or any control date
range scenarios.
OK,
here you're getting right any bag dated
range.
So I'm on July 23rd,
but there is a like there is a change in
the some some change happened in my
source system.
They want to do a rerun,
rerun for from July 1st to to July 23rd I
think.
So for this scenario,
I'll consider this scenario as a rerun
and then what I'll do as far so rerun
will will only be considered when there
is a change, right?
We don't know.
We don't know it.
It is basically if we want to do a
control a rerun like a data for a batch
run must be processed for a specific bag
dated date range or a control date range
scenario.
Here you are, you are getting right.
If we want to do any data load for a
specific date range,
it can be due to anything.
Anything any change but that in that case
the first time incremental also comes
under this, right?
For those three days,
first time incremental is different RIA
that is different that that run is where
we are trying to load from source to zone
to like from first time incremental is
related to the data load happening from
zone 1 to zone 2 where zone 1 would be
getting data from directly from the
source system.
OK, that is different.
This is different.
Rerun is different.
That is only one time process.
This rerun can happen multiple times in
the future.
OK,
that is we are how how like we are
getting the data like how the let me
complete let me complete the below steps
also.
Yeah,
so affair like this is the scenario then
we'll take that run as a rerun and new
record will be created manually in batch
run stats and new execution run ID will
be assigned.
Rerun indicator would be why status would
be started sourcing start time sourcing
end time will be populated as required
because we don't know the date range,
right.
So this will be populated as per
requirement.
Next during read and processing batch
prerequisite will not be evaluated.
Previous executed tables associated with
the batch will be reexecuted after the
manual cleanup.
Existing target records will be hard
deleted based on the application load
type and impacted audit job ID,
create date, time and audit update values.
All these will be hard deleted OK since
the records are created manually in in 2
batch run stats,
batch preload will not perform any
additional change and execution will
additional change.
Yes.
OK will not perform any additional
changes and execution will begin at drop
preload.
It means no.
So here it is.
It is.
It is already stating that entry is
creating manually.
That means it it is.
It won't do that.
Batch reload won't do any entry here.
OK, what is this audit batch ID?
This this is related to this is an audit
column in target tables.
OK, it is name and audit batch ID.
OK,
so I'm just given here like target
request deletion would be there, right?
It would be based on the load type audit
unpacked, audit batch ID, create data,
update data.
I'm just I'm just giving that we might
need use these tables for deleting the
records from targeted for the cleanup.
OK,
so manually we need to delete records
from target table, correct?
And execution time.
And what is the second point?
This manual cleanup?
What is this manual cleanup?
Both the same.
So both the same is wait, sorry, yeah,
for rerun whatever the tables that are
loaded successfully in the previous run,
those will also be daily.
Those will also be reprocessed for that
reprocess before the rerun itself we have
to delete the data from our targets.
But the based upon the requirement
whatever the data or whatever the batch
related information needs to be deleted.
Based upon that information we have like
manual cleanup should be performed.
I am describing how that manual cleanup
can be done using load type and impacted
audit, Batch ID audit create them,
updated these using these target columns
we can do the hard delete.
This is what I'm mentioning OK here.
And last point is just as a record is
already created manually,
batch window will not perform any
additional changes or any entry or
anything.
The the process will be manual clean up
process entirely for reason it is manual
clean up, OK.
And this is already implemented.
There is no change needed for this, right?
Yeah, no,
you don't need to do it is already
implemented will not perform any changes,
additional changes or any any new and OK
execution time would be redone.
OK.
And like I would with redone and restart,
Yeah,
for now we'll check through the document,
right?
OK.
Yeah, if you have any question,
just go through this recording again.
And like most of the questions I felt is
which is already covered yesterday.
So if you have any, anything,
just go through this recording again.
I think most of your questions would be
answered if anything,
which I have not covered like we can
discuss this tomorrow because the call is
taking a lot of time, right?
That is the reason why I'm asking you who
are you?
So zone 1 rerun execution.
If zone 2 must be rerun because due to a
rerun of zone 2 then this process is
called zone 1 rerun.
For this,
as part of ABC we would be creating a
manual entry into batch and stats and
your execution run ID would be assigned,
rerun indicator would be Z and status
would be started.
During a zone 1 rerun,
batch prerequisites will not be evaluated.
Batch will not perform any additional
because the entry is created manually and
execution becomes at job reload.
No target table will be done here.
No target table cleanup would be done in
case of a zone 1 rerun and the value for
this execution time.
But in that case also there could be some
changes in data, right?
So why is not done?
Yeah, like I don't know.
This is the information that I got for a
zone 1 rerun.
They are saying there is no need to do a
data cleanup.
They're handling everything.
Within the source to stage code only.
So in case of a zoneman rerun,
if the data for a particular key is
changing, they are updating that record.
They are having the logic in place to
handle backdated data within the source
query itself.
So that is the reason why they are not
doing this target data cleanup in case of
Zoneman rerun.
OK hello I thought I thought you got a
network issue.
OK let me so I I don't know Ishwari if
there is any like table or something but
if not can you after this redone zone 1
rerun step in the LD can you add a table
with different redone flags?
What is the significance of it one day
like 3 columns?
What is the value of the redone flag and
what is the complete name of that?
Yeah.
And what is the purpose of display one
table?
I just with all the flow and then code
also.
Yeah, I'll give you that table,
but I need some time because I have to
work on also.
So.
Oh no, that that is fine.
I'm just telling you,
just keep a note of it so it will be
easier.
OK,
So here based upon whatever the base of
so we'll get the batch ID from the batch
metadata table, right?
Based upon the batch ID,
we will be looking into the batch run
stretch to get the latest run details.
Like we'll take a status and trade run
flag mostly high level.
I'm telling you here.
So if my batch to run flag is N,
then I'll check if my status is failed or
started.
If it is either failed or started then it
will check if my status is failed it
started again.
If it is started then it will just update
the entry in the batch run states from
started to fail and then it will make a
new entry with a same execution run ID
and status has started and it will assume
this execution type has restart.
If the status is not equal to started
then it would be failed right here as I'm
getting from this.
So if it is failed then my I'll just make
a new entry into the batch run stats with
the same execution run ID with status
started and execution type would be
restart here.
OK moving back.
So if my batch run stats is not failed,
not started then it will make an insert
in a new entry in batch transacts with
status has started.
So if it is not failed or not started
then it would be completed right?
So if my previous status is completed
then it it is my regular run.
So we are passing the execution type as
new and then coming one step back again.
If my rerun flag is not equal to north
then it can be a scenario of rerun read
and scenario.
So here we have implemented for as this
historical came now like they like we are
we are actually implemented.
So we don't have that logic in place and
this is also not updated.
OK, I have just sorry,
this flow is not updated,
but I have just added those details in so
that it would be easy for me to give you
the details.
OK.
And then we would be passing execution
type as a rerun.
If the batch data and flag equal to Y.
If if the execution type is zone 1
written,
then if exactly if batch data and flag
equal to C,
then we would passing the execution type
as zone one reader.
We'll pass batch ID execution,
run ID execution,
type all those to the next component,
downstream component,
and we'll exit the batch.
Batch failures, then we'll have OK,
now let me go to IDMC.
Let me log in again.
I'll show you the code for the batch
preload so that we can end our call post
this.
The preload is scheduled for tomorrow.
I think you just can show me the inputs
and all whatever it is from the batch.
Yeah,
but batch batch preload is not completed
rightly.
I haven't showed you the code for batch
preload.
Let's come first.
OK,
post that like let's let's wrap this code
to even.
I'm not feeling like I'm not able to
explain you.
I'm feeling hungry already.
You, you, you,
you can inform like that it is taking
such time.
And also like if you,
if you need like you can break,
break it down to two sessions because it
is, yeah,
difficult for everyone to what I feeling
is if I cover ABC in the fastest half or
before lunch so that I can focus
peacefully on CCO, because CCO,
I cannot estimate the time on CCO.
I don't know how it is going.
Oh my God.
OK, let me take.
I took it from you.
But for today's like it is 2 1/2 hour.
It already took.
Yeah,
let's inform like it is taking around 3
hours because reverse KDS itself is
taking time and also this like it's a
very small thing only this is only taking
this much of time, then job preload,
I don't know, yeah, will take a lot.
But if I do not understand individually
then like in case any surprise comes
right in the way,
then that will be difficult and I do not
want to disturb special occasion.
OK so here first it we are passing source
source name, domain name,
application layer name,
target zone in the parameter file.
So,
and also I'm using Ease active flag OK if
it is Y Based upon these values,
I would be fetching the batch ID and
source batch ID from batch metadata table.
Source batch ID,
application source batch ID means the
zone 1 batch ID, right?
Correct, Correct.
Yeah.
And then latest run.
So we are trying to get the latest run
from batch run stats table using the
batch ID that we got from the metadata
table.
No, it's OK.
This is the same.
I think this in this one.
Yeah, earlier also.
So here I am,
I'm trying to do fetch from metadata
table by doing a left join with latest
run where my batch ID equal to this
latest run batch ID.
What is this that is different?
Sorry RIA.
So first time getting the batch details
OK using these parameters only I'm trying
to bring the batch ID,
application source batch ID and batch
name OK and previous so.
So here I'm trying to get the most recent
run details for this batch.
So using the batch ID that I've got above,
I'm trying to get the latest batch run
details.
Like I'm trying to get the batch run ID
execution run ID status free run flag
sourcing start and sourcing antenna from
from the latest entry latest run.
OK.
And I'm also getting the latest source
run.
OK, in the second in the third city,
I'm trying to get the latest source run.
So here I'm trying to get yeah,
you will get an why I'm doing all these
things.
You'll get you'll get it once I complete
it.
OK,
get the latest completed or partial run
of the source batch.
OK so we are trying to based upon the
application source batch ID which I got
in the first city.
Using that I'm trying to get the get the
latest source back strand details.
So latest not like my requirement here is
I'm trying to get the latest completed or
partial run.
So that is the reason why in philtre
condition I'm taking status equal to
completed or partial.
It's like for the source base I I'm
trying to get the latest no.
Here in case of target batch we are
directly getting the latest batch run but
in source we are trying to get the latest
completed or partial run details.
OK,
so this that is the reason why we are
using this philtre.
We are just bringing execution and ID job
and time,
sorry batch and time and application
source batch IDs.
And then here in the final select clause,
we're trying to join all the three CTS
above and trying to bring batch ID,
batch name from the first city and
previous batch run ID execution and ID
state test data and flag from the This is
these are related to the previous run of
this batch and this is the latest
completed run details.
OK.
And these are audit columns.
So we have to populate current timestamp
at UTC to this audit fields.
So and also we need we are using Gen
random UAID.
This is a function in order of post which
is used it to generate UAID value.
So I'll be using it in case of any new
entry I have like sometimes I have to
populate new execution and ID new batch
and ID, right.
So for that purpose,
I'm just getting them.
And then then my answer to my question is
this like new and this execution and ID
and batch run ID then we'll never the
same, right?
In that case, no, no,
it will be always different.
That's back then for the first time and
low end it I'm just giving this but it it
is of no use.
But as this first time incremental has
and historical catch up related logic has
not been implemented it,
I'm just using this so that my sourcing
and time won't be null every time.
OK, this is all it used, right?
That's it.
This is the source query.
So here whatever we are drinking out of
the source query,
we would be using in the latest steps of
the mapping, OK.
And then here in the expression
transformation in the expression first
insert flag.
So if my previous status is either
started, OK let me open this.
If my previous status that means previous
status in the sense this is related to
this batch, current batch,
whatever target batch shown to batch it,
if it is started and my batch rerun flag
is either Y or N,
then my insert flag I use a ZZ means what
Y is shown to rerun OK, zone 1 rerun.
So in these cases, in these two cases,
as I have implemented only for new
restart zone one return zone to return.
That is the reason why I I have only
these.
So in case of zone one return or zone 2
return,
I should not make any entry as part of
batch speed load, right?
That is the reason why I'm just using
this not flag not to make any insert OK.
I'm keeping this flag value as 0 OK and
then insert status.
So if I like I'm just using this status
whenever I I have to make any insert
always my status would be started right
in case of here.
So that is that is why I kept it as hard
put it and insert execution and ID OK if
my previous status is null.
So if for my drone to batch,
if my previous status is null,
that should not be the case.
But if my previous status is equal to
null or previous status equal to
completed then it is a regular scenario
right?
It is a regular scenario.
The previous status like it is the target
zone, zone 2 map status, Yeah,
Zone 2 batch status is either null or
completed.
Then we have to populate new execution
run ID.
Else we have to use previous execution
run ID.
So we would be making entry into this
batch run stats only during new or
regular run and during restart, correct.
So we're just in case of new run,
we have to use a new execution run ID,
otherwise we have to use the previous
execution run ID.
In case of restart we have to use the
previous execution run ID OK so OK and
the the insurance flat can I go back to
that one second which one OK first one
first No no first one first expression OK.
So this means if previous status is
started and if if it is a zone one or
zone 2D run that means 0 means that is
not a insert.
Is it like what is the significance on
this?
Yeah, we would be using this flag later.
OK, OK.
And then what is it insert execution and
whatever the execution run ID that like
during insert, whatever the execution run,
I'm just applying it here.
And then read and flag would be end.
So either in during restart or new run
whatever we are making we're doing insert
using this component,
using this mapping read and flag would be
wise.
It would be end.
So that is the given output value update
flag.
So in case of restart if my previous
status is started then I have to update
get it to failed right?
That is on me right?
That is on right.
So the here I'm doing status is stay
started then we have to make it as failed.
OK I'm using previous status as started
and previous read and flag is equal to
north then this is my restart scenario.
OK then I'm I need to do 1 update this is
update flag I think why then it is
restarts the scenario right?
Rerun, rerun scenario?
If it is,
why then it is rerun scenario OK, OK,
OK N meets restart scenario OK While
updating we are using the previous to
update it OK and update status would be
failed.
We have to update the starter to fail now.
So update status is failed set execution
right?
So we have to pass few parameters to next
component from this component.
So I'm just setting those values.
So using parameters for for those
parameters using set variable.
So first I'm setting execution run ID
which is whatever the execution run ID
which I'm passing I'm I'm setting it here.
Give me this address previous extreme run
ID, OK,
So OK in any other cases whatever the
previous execution run ID that I have,
in case of rerun also this value.
So let's consider it's a rerun scenario
then this V execution run ID,
what it will hold,
it will hold previous execution run ID.
So in this case, we don't make any entry,
but whatever the previous execution run
ID which we have would be assigned to
this particular variable would be set to
this particular variable and batch ID
also.
I'm setting the batch ID OK,
whatever the batch ID that I got from my
and sourcing start time.
Here I'm just trying to give the output
expression for populating the sourcing
start time.
OK,
let me open this sourcing start and if my
status is null so I'm giving low ended.
Otherwise if my previous status is
completed then I'm giving previous
sources started else the previous source
OK, OK, OK, you got it now.
OK, then previous source batch end time.
So whatever the source patch end time
that we got from this query,
now we are just like assigning that to
this parameter and then source execution
run ID is also same whatever the
execution run ID that we got out of that
query.
What is the sourcing ended time?
Source Standard Time I got what is the
end?
OK, here we are.
No, no, sorry I skipped sourcing end time.
If it is new new new scenario then we
would be using previous then we would be
using batch end time.
Otherwise previous sourcing end time.
So here I'm like while populating the
value.
My intention is here.
Here is if it is regular run then use
source batch end time.
Source batch end time in the sense join
one batch end time OK that is for regular
scenario.
That is the requirement in case if I am
doing restart then use the previous
sourcing end type.
That's what I mentioned in the document.
OK and moving on to this.
So execution type here I have handled
rerun zone 1, rerun new and restart there.
There are 4 execution types I have
handled and three are yet to be
incorporated.
If my previous flag equal to rerun flag
equal to Y then it is rerun.
If my previous batch T run flag equal to
Z then it is zone 1 rerun.
If my previous status is null or if it is
completed then it is a new.
If my previous status is started or
previous status is failed then it is a
restart.
Otherwise it is not OK.
This is the execution type,
OK and we are keeping it in a variable
field and we are sending it to output
field where is we are setting,
we are setting the execution runtime here
this side OK have to like go through 1st
or go through it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Source.
But whenever you get some time like even
if you're not able to like with
formatting and all,
you're not able to update it in MLD right
now,
but you can send me a doc or anything.
OK?
For this different,
we don't flags or match,
we don't flag or something, right?
So this is very confusing for,
I know like you were used to it,
that's why it is easy.
But for me it is yeah.
Like even after this,
like while you are going through the
recording or going through the code,
right, you can also make a note of it.
I'll,
I can check and I'll let you know if it
is correct or anyway you are making the
notes doing like preparing the notes
after this discussion, right.
And not everything like overall like what
I understood this one like this.
I can give him plans.
But like I I'm just telling you because
all the details are here.
So if you will look at this expression,
if you give this to Copilot also,
it will it can also create it.
I can also create it using Copilot just
giving this expression.
Yeah, I, I can give that OK.
And source execution and ID,
source batch ID,
whatever we are getting from the source
query,
we are sending it here and source batch
ID also and batch ID also.
So whatever we are getting from the batch
metadata table,
we're sending it and we are passing all
this value slate.
And here in the router,
we are using two output groups,
one with insert flag 11 with update flag
1.
So whatever record that needs to be
inserted would be inserted here.
Whatever that needs to be updated would
be updated here.
OK, based off what?
Whatever the feeds that needs to be
inserted,
I mapped only those feeds in here.
You can go through it.
Let me if you have any questions here in
one quick question in which case like it
will be like more things that an update
will be happening in case of restart with
previous status as started.
OK, I have to go through this code.
What is happening and expect Yeah, yeah,
that's what they are here.
Also while updating we will be using the
previous batch run ID and we we will be
updating batch end time status and audit
updated and audit updated by user ID.
We can go through this logic you you will
get it.
Got it.
That's it, Ria,
like if you have any questions, right,
just go through this recording.
I,
I think I have covered almost everything
and you have,
you have almost all the questions.
So whatever the questions that you marked
as code, walk through, right.
Just like go,
go through the recording and try to give
the answers for them.
We can validate it too.
OK, Yeah, OK.
Yeah, then thank you.
OK, Thank you for yeah, yeah,
I give you my, Yeah, my.